categories_coll = {
    'geography': 'geography',
    'history': 'history',
    'science': 'science'
}


questions_coll = [
    {
        'id': 1,
        'question': 'Who is the author of the anthem of Uzbekistan?',
        'difficulty': 3,
        'answer': 'Abdulla Aripov',
        'category': 'geography'
    },
    {
        'id': 2,
        'question': 'Who is the first president of Uzbekistan?',
        'difficulty': 2,
        'answer': 'Islam Karimov',
        'category': 'geography'
    },
    {
        'id': 3,
        'question': 'On what year did Uzbekistan declare independence?',
        'difficulty': 3,
        'answer': '1991',
        'category': 'geography'
    },
    {
        'id': 4,
        'question': 'What is the name of the second president of Uzbekistan?',
        'difficulty': 1,
        'answer': 'Shavkat Mirziyaev',
        'category': 'geography'
    },
    {
        'id': 5,
        'question': 'What is the northen neighbor of Uzbekistan?',
        'difficulty': 4,
        'answer': 'Kazakhstan',
        'category': 'geography'
    },
    {
        'id': 6,
        'question': 'Is population of Uzbeksistan larger than 30 million?',
        'difficulty': 1,
        'answer': 'Yes',
        'category': 'geography'
    },
    {
        'id': 7,
        'question': 'To whom does this quote belong: "I prefer a short life with width to a narrow one with length."',
        'difficulty': 5,
        'answer': 'Avicenna',
        'category': 'science'
    },
    {
        'id': 8,
        'question': 'To whom does this quote belong: "My own soul is my most faithful friend. My own heart, my trust confidant."',
        'difficulty': 5,
        'answer': 'Babur',
        'category': 'science'
    },
    {
        'id': 9,
        'question': 'Who is the national hero is Uzbekistan?',
        'difficulty': 2,
        'answer': 'Amir Temur',
        'category': 'history'
    },
    {
        'id': 10,
        'question': 'Whot was the capital of Amir Timur\'s country?',
        'difficulty': 4,
        'answer': 'Samarkand',
        'category': 'history'
    },
    {
        'id': 11,
        'question': 'Who is the greatest grandson of Amir Timur?',
        'difficulty': 2,
        'answer': 'Ulugh Bek',
        'category': 'history'
    },
    {
        'id': 12,
        'question': 'Who was Ulugh Bek\'s father?',
        'difficulty': 4,
        'answer': 'Shakhrukh',
        'category': 'history'
    },
    {
        'id': 13,
        'question': 'How did arabs call the territory above Amu Darya?',
        'difficulty': 4,
        'answer': 'Mawarannahr',
        'category': 'history'
    },
    {
        'id': 15,
        'question': 'The name of what city is "rich settlement"?',
        'difficulty': 5,
        'answer': 'Samarkand',
        'category': 'history'
    },
    {
        'id': 16,
        'question': 'Who is the most known poet of Timurid period?',
        'difficulty': 3,
        'answer': 'Ali Shir Nava\'i',
        'category': 'history'
    },
    {
        'id': 17,
        'question': 'What language was used in Timurid empire?',
        'difficulty': 5,
        'answer': 'Chagatai',
        'category': 'history'
    },
    {
        'id': 18,
        'question': 'Which dynasty brought "Uzbek" name to Timurid nations?',
        'difficulty': 4,
        'answer': 'Shaybanid',
        'category': 'history'
    },
    {
        'id': 19,
        'question': 'In what year did mongols besiege Samarkand?',
        'difficulty': 4,
        'answer': '1220',
        'category': 'history'
    },
    {
        'id': 20,
        'question': 'What was the name of the Kharesm emperor that oppossed Ghengis Khan?',
        'difficulty': 4,
        'answer': 'Mukhammad',
        'category': 'history'
    },
    {
        'id': 21,
        'question': 'What name did Vyatkin give to the ruins that were left by mongols?',
        'difficulty': 2,
        'answer': 'Afrosiab',
        'category': 'history'
    },
    {
        'id': 22,
        'question': 'What was the main tool of Ulug Bek\'s observatory?',
        'difficulty': 4,
        'answer': 'Sekstant',
        'category': 'history'
    },
    {
        'id': 23,
        'question': 'Is it true that Uzbek and Turkish belong to the same language family?',
        'difficulty': 3,
        'answer': 'Yes',
        'category': 'history'
    },
    {
        'id': 24,
        'question': 'Is it true that many people in Samarkand speak Tajik?',
        'difficulty': 1,
        'answer': 'Yes',
        'category': 'history'
    }
]